<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-13T07:23:57+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Isabel Figueroa</title><entry><title type="html">How Ender Wiggin Exhibits U.S. General Jim Mattis’s Prefered Leadership Qualities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/04/09/call-sign-chaos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Ender Wiggin Exhibits U.S. General Jim Mattis’s Prefered Leadership Qualities" /><published>2022-04-09T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-04-09T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/04/09/call-sign-chaos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/04/09/call-sign-chaos.html">&lt;p&gt;Retired U.S. General Jim Mattis’s memoir, &lt;em&gt;Call Sign Chaos&lt;/em&gt; (2019), and Orson
Scott Card’s novel, &lt;em&gt;Ender’s Game&lt;/em&gt; (1977), showcase the same qualities of a
strong military leader. In &lt;em&gt;Call Sign Chaos&lt;/em&gt;, four-star General Mattis describes
his experience in the Marine Corps, and communicates how a leader should behave,
form a successful team, and which skills to build. In &lt;em&gt;Ender’s Game&lt;/em&gt;, young
Ender Wiggin focuses on himself, his team, and the critical military skills in
exactly the way General Mattis recommends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-leader&quot;&gt;The Leader&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As military leaders, General Jim Mattis and Commander Ender Wiggin both model
authority, scholarship, and trust. General Mattis praises the leadership of one
of his own regimental commanders, Colonel Carl Fulford. He remembers Colonel
Fulford as:  “…firm yet unfailingly polite, he never had to raise his voice.
He simply assumed you would meet his high standards. And you did - because you
did not want to disappoint him” (p. 22). Colonel Fulford maintains a
gentlemanly, calm demeanor, and sets high expectations. His soldiers feel
motivated to earn his approval. General Mattis also explains that leaders must
remain somewhat removed from the soldiers under their command. He advises:
“Consistently maintain a social and personal distance…You are not their friend.
You are their coach and commander, rewarding the qualities essential to
battle-field victory” (p. 12). Like Colonel Fulford, Ender exhibits a quiet calm
and expectation of excellence: “…when [Ender] worked with an individual he was
always patient, explaining as often as necessary, making suggestions quietly…”
(p. 129). Ender’s behavior also aligns with General Mattis’s recommendation to
never stray from the leadership role. As Ender trains with his Dragon Army
troops, Ender “… was commander every moment they were together. He never had
to remind them of it; he simply was” (p. 129). Ender’s role as the leader is
fixed - his behavior creates the separation between himself and his troops that
General Mattis deems necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that leaders can ensure that they deserve their authority is to
commit themselves to lifelong education. According to General Mattis, leaders
that educate themselves regarding the lessons of past battles make the best
decisions in the next fights. He explains: “Before going into battle, you can
learn by asking veterans about their experience and by reading relentlessly…By
studying how others have dealt with similar circumstances, I became exposed to
leadership examples that accelerated my expanding understanding of combat” (p.
41). General Mattis urges leaders to learn about the perspectives and actions of
past leaders. Ender informs and prepares himself for upcoming battles with the
primary sources at his disposal - footage from past battles:  “[Ender] began to
use the video room, filled with propaganda vids about Mazer Rackham and other
great commanders of the forces of humanity in the First and Second Invasion…by
watching them in sequence, Ender was able to reconstruct whole battles’’ (p.
132-133). Ender studies the moves of the most famous veterans of his army -
especially Mazer Rackham. Ender’s independent study of previous battles allows
him to see the outcomes of other leaders’ tried tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides consistent authority and a high level of scholarship, leaders must
practice displays of trust for their teams in order to inspire them. General
Mattis imparts: “… it’s not enough to trust your people; you must be able to
convey that trust in a manner that subordinates can sense. Only then can you
fully garner the benefits…” (p. 239). General Mattis explains that as a leader,
he can not assume that his troops know how he feels about them. Leaders must
clearly express their trust in subordinates. General Mattis believes that
expressions of trust build morale and earn leaders loyalty and high performing
troops. Ender voices his faith in his Dragon Army when he says to them before an
upcoming challenge: “‘…I do like one thing - that I’ve got an army that can
handle it.’ After that, if he had asked them to follow him to the moon without
space suits, they would have done it” (p. 131). Ender explicitly tells his
soldiers that he trusts them - that he knows they can manage the challenges they
face. His army responds with unconditional loyalty and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-team&quot;&gt;The Team&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Mattis insists that leaders must cultivate a cohesive team of soldiers,
with effective lines of communication, and empowered sub-commanders. General
Mattis warns, “Strangers who haven’t trained together don’t work smoothly
together. Once in the fray, they need to work out the kinks. Ideally, they
rehearse repeatedly before an operation…” (p. 69). General Mattis explains that
when they first begin to train together, troops experience clumsy collaboration.
In order to be effective, a new team requires time to practice together before a
real battle. Furthermore, General Mattis teaches, “…you need to ensure that
[soldiers] are in the same unit long enough to know their brothers and develop
trust and confidence in one another” (p. 27). General Mattis stresses that
positive feelings among team members are fundamental, and take time to grow.
Ender appreciates the importance of team training and bonding. When a group of
older boys attacks Ender and his team of young Launchies, Ender sees that,
“…the enemy was coming haphazardly, uncoordinatedly; they had never worked
together before, while Ender’s little practice army, though there were only a
dozen of them now, knew each other well and knew how to work together” (p. 81).
Ender does not have many troops, and the ones he does have are smaller and
younger than their attackers. However, Ender’s troops do have the tremendous
benefit of prior team training and mutual trust. Ender and his cohesive team
prevail against the bullies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once team members are familiar with one another, General Mattis explains that
leaders must maintain open communication throughout the ranks. A leader’s
intentions must reach the lowest ranking individuals, and the feelings of the
youngest, newest troops must be able to reach their commander. General Mattis
stresses that intent must be “passed intact through the layers of intermediate
leadership to our youngest Marines” (p. 43). A mission’s success relies on a
team’s common understanding of the purpose. The youngest, newest, and most
entry-level team members must have a precise understanding of their commander’s
goals. General Mattis also feels that as a leader, “If you can’t talk freely
with the most junior members of your organization, then you’ve lost your touch”
(p. 50). General Mattis engages with soldiers of every rank in order to maintain
an accurate sense of his team’s mood. When Ender becomes a commander, “He also
knew that he didn’t intend to be like many commanders, who never even saw the
younger boys because they were always in the back” (p. 112). Ender wants to have
access to all of his troops. As the leader, he does not want to be disconnected
from anyone, even the lowest-ranking soldiers, under his command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to General Mattis, when sub-commanders clearly understand their
commander’s intentions, they are able to thrive in an environment of
decentralized power. General Mattis advises: “Leave the ‘how’ to your
subordinates, who must be trained and rewarded for exercising initiative, taking
advantage of opportunities and problems as they arise” (p. 44). General Mattis
believes that when he properly communicates his intentions throughout the ranks,
he empowers his capable subordinates to make the best decisions at a fast pace.
Ender observes how Bonzo leads his team, and identifies a mistake Bonzo makes:
“…the individual soldiers were given little initiative. Once a pattern was
set, they were to follow it through. There was no room for adjustment to what
the enemy did against the formation” (p. 61). Unfortunately, Bonzo keeps
decision-making power centralized. Bonzo’s toon leaders thus waste
opportunities. When Ender becomes the commander of his own Dragon Army, “…he
trained his toon leaders to use their small units effectively in achieving
limited goals. Unsupported, alone, on their own initiative…tactical decisions
were entirely up to the toon leaders” (p. 124, 126). Ender trains his toon
leaders to be independent leaders. Once Ender’s toon leaders understand the end
goals, they are able to determine themselves how they reach those goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-skills&quot;&gt;The Skills&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Mattis focuses on mastery of the fundamentals, flexibility, and speed.
First, he urges soldiers to “Be brilliant in the basics. Don’t dabble in your
job; you must master it…you need to make sure that your training is so hard and
varied that it removes complacency and creates muscle memory—instinctive
reflexes…” (p. 11, 27). He claims that when soldiers commit themselves to
mastery of basic skills, those skills will be quickly available to them in any
situation. Soldiers that train their bodies to memorize the movements of
critical tasks can depend on the automatic movements in stressful situations.
When Ender becomes leader of an army, he knows “He had to have a well-trained
army, and that meant drilling the soldiers over and over again, long after they
thought they had mastered a technique, until it was so natural to them that they
didn’t have to think about it anymore” (p. 119). In line with General Mattis’s
advice, Ender leads his troops towards mastery by way of rigorous training.
Eventually, the training allows Ender’s troops to consistently exhibit correct
responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastery of the basics allows soldiers to execute another essential skill which
General Mattis highlights: speed. The General shares that “Speed is essential,
whether in sports, business, or combat, because time is the least forgiving,
least recoverable factor in any competitive situation” (p. 238). He warns that
delayed response or slow movements can be punishing, and cause defeat for an
otherwise strong army. General Mattis stresses, “…you have to observe what is
going on, orient yourself, decide what to do, and act before your opponent has
completed his version of the same process, repeating and repeating this loop
faster than your foe” (p. 90). General Mattis strives for OODA (observe, orient,
decide, act) loops faster than his enemy’s. Ender wins battles because of his
ability to cause damage quickly, before his enemy can. Colonel Graff asks Ender
how his army is so successful and Ender replies: “…our enemies haven’t the
time to respond effectively to our new techniques, so we keep beating them…” (p.
134). Ender’s key strategy is speed, which keeps his enemies defensive and
disorganized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, soldiers must remain agile. Regarding agility, General Mattis remembers
his own leader, Colonel Fulford, again. In the Colonel’s words, “If one thing
isn’t working, change to another. Shift gears. Don’t lose momentum. Improvise”
(p. 25). During battle, soldiers must be able to recognize futility, adapt, and
implement a new strategy. Ender considers agility when he thinks about how he
will train a new soldier. Ender decides that he will keep the soldier “…off
balance, never sure what’s going to happen next, so [he is] ready for anything,
ready to improvise, determined to win no matter what” (p. 119). Ender trains
soldiers to expect the unexpected. A soldier accustomed to new situations can
think of creative solutions, and deliver appropriate strategies quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although forty years separates the two books, &lt;em&gt;Call Sign Chaos&lt;/em&gt; (2019) and
&lt;em&gt;Ender’s Game&lt;/em&gt; (1977) value the same portrait of a leader. General Jim Mattis
plainly relates the traits of a successful leader, and Ender Wiggin embodies
those traits. The U.S. military leader and the fictional character both value an
authoritative, educated, and inspiring leader - one that is able to build a
cohesive, communicative, and empowered team. Across the years and genres, the
two military texts also value the enduring principles of mastery, speed, and
flexibility in battle. The Marine Corps’s Commandant’s Professional Reading List
includes &lt;em&gt;Call Sign Chaos&lt;/em&gt; in its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mca-marines.org/commandants-professional-reading-list/&quot;&gt;Leadership&lt;/a&gt;
section, and &lt;em&gt;Ender’s Game&lt;/em&gt; in its
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mca-marines.org/blog/resource/commandants-professional-reading-list/&quot;&gt;Foundational&lt;/a&gt;
section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card, O.S. 1977. &lt;em&gt;Ender’s game&lt;/em&gt;. Tom Doherty Associates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mattis, J. &amp;amp; West, B. 2019. &lt;em&gt;Call sign Chaos: Learning to lead&lt;/em&gt;. Random House.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="13-15" /><summary type="html">Retired U.S. General Jim Mattis’s memoir, Call Sign Chaos (2019), and Orson Scott Card’s novel, Ender’s Game (1977), showcase the same qualities of a strong military leader. In Call Sign Chaos, four-star General Mattis describes his experience in the Marine Corps, and communicates how a leader should behave, form a successful team, and which skills to build. In Ender’s Game, young Ender Wiggin focuses on himself, his team, and the critical military skills in exactly the way General Mattis recommends.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/call-sign-chaos.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/call-sign-chaos.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Struggle of a Journalist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/18+/2022/03/21/on-all-fronts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Struggle of a Journalist" /><published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/18+/2022/03/21/on-all-fronts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/18+/2022/03/21/on-all-fronts.html">&lt;p&gt;In the 2020 memoir, &lt;em&gt;On All Fronts&lt;/em&gt;, CNN’s chief international correspondent,
Clarissa Ward, exhibits her perseverance throughout frustrating experiences that
make her doubt her work. As a teenager, Clarissa Ward expresses her desire to
help people: “I can understand people and convey their ideas. I’m a
communicator” (p. 25). The desire to understand people and facilitate
communication intensifies following the terrorist attacks in the United States
on September 11, 2001, while Clarissa attends college. In the wake of the
attacks, she relates: “I knew I had to go to the front lines, to hear the
stories of people who lived there and tell them to the people back home” (p.
24). Clarissa Ward enters the field of journalism as a young adult, and during
her career, travels around the world to listen to people and share their stories
with the public. In her memoir, Clarissa Ward illustrates her persistence,
despite recurring feelings of guilt regarding what she perceives as her
emotional, material, and journalistic shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;emotional-support&quot;&gt;Emotional Support&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ward regularly meets ordinary people in crisis situations, which brings her into
highly emotional times in their lives. During the Syrian uprising against
president Bashar al-Assad, Ward speaks to a Syrian man as he grieves the death
of his son, a shooting victim of Bashar al-Assad’s security force. Ward recalls
her meeting with the mourning father: “I watched his hands, fidgeting constantly
with fear and grief. I wanted to take them in mine and hold them, to put down
the camera for a minute and be a human being. But I knew the only way I could
help him was to make sure that people heard his story. I prompted him to keep
going…” (p. 5). Ward speaks with the Syrian father at an tremendously painful
time in his life, and her instinct tells her to console the man. She decides
that she is more helpful if she shares the man’s pain with the world, and she
chooses to continue the difficult interview. At other times in Syria, Ward
simply can’t find the right way to express herself. She explains her farewell to
a group of heroic Syrian medics that she comes to know: “We said our goodbyes to
Bulbul and the others, and I felt the familiar pang that came with wanting to be
able to give them a big hug and tell them how remarkable I thought they were.
But custom and my limited Arabic skills only permitted me to hold my hand to my
heart and thank them effusively” (p. 213). Ward mentions the inappropriateness
of physical contact and her insufficient language ability as reasons why she
feels dissatisfied at their parting. Perhaps, though, no gestures or words can
ever properly communicate feelings of awe and respect - even between people from
a similar culture and language background. In Yemen, Ward visits a woman named
Soumaya and her severely malnourished five-year-old son, Ahmed Helmi. At that
time, Ward is not only unable to offer any comfort, she becomes upset herself.
Ward remembers: “[Ahmed] looked up at me briefly and I was suddenly seized by a
wrenching sob. Soumaya put her hand on my arm. I was ashamed that she was
comforting me when her son was dying” (p. 296). Throughout her reporting,
Clarissa Ward struggles as she obtains people’s stories while unable to offer
much consolation in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tangible-help&quot;&gt;Tangible Help&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people Ward encounters need practical assistance, which she usually cannot
provide. In Iraq around 2005, Ward takes Arabic lessons with a man named Hakim.
The father of four children, Hakim eventually asks Clarissa if she can help him
get his family to a safer country. Clarissa shares, “It was a question I would
be asked dozens and dozens of times as a reporter working in some of the most
dangerous places in the world. And it would not get any easier to answer. There
was always the burn of shame ” (p. 52). As a dual citizen - an American and
British passport holder - Ward travels with relative ease around the world. Her
own privilege, however, does not allow her to share that privilege with the
others she meets. When desperate people such as Hakim ask her for help, she
struggles with the reality that a man’s nationality can so greatly dictate his
life. One Syrian friend, Mohammed, asks Ward to answer for an entire nation when
he presses her on the lack of aid from the United States. Ward recalls
Mohammed’s questions: “Why did America do nothing to save the Syrian people, he
asked angrily, while the Russians and Iranians were helping the regime to kill
them?” (p. 255). With Muhammed, Ward seems to bear not only personal
responsibility, but national responsibility as well. Frustrated, Mohammed
demands that Ward explain her country’s inaction. Even when she does have the
power to help, however, Ward explains her position as a reporter: “Strictly
speaking, you’re not supposed to give money or charity to interview subjects
because it can look as though you’re paying someone to tell their story and that
can potentially affect what they tell you” (p. 284). Ward understands that many
of the people she meets need paperwork, supplies, or money and generally, she is
not the person to supply that material support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;journalistic-effect&quot;&gt;Journalistic Effect&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of emotional or tangible support, Ward tries to focus on the help that
she actually can offer, which is to share people’s stories with the rest of the
world. What Ward &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do is draw attention to human suffering and amplify
voices in need. However, doubts about her work as a reporter creep into her mind
as well. She wants to convey the true natures of the people she meets, but fears
that she does not do these people justice: “There were so many small acts of
kindness by sincere people that would never make it onto the evening news. These
were the things that moved me to the core…” (p. 265). Real people - what they
endure, overcome, and the goodness they exhibit in difficult circumstances -
impress her. She knows that her face to face contact with people helps her
understand them better, while consumers of the news around the world only obtain
select words, images, or videos. She doubts that she captures and shares the
most compelling glimpse of the people she gets to know. She also worries,
“Outside of the media bubble, would the pieces have any meaningful
impact?…Perhaps, in the great majority of American households, the tragedy of
Syria was a momentary distraction before the trash was put out and the kids were
told to finish their homework” (p. 170). She wonders if her reporting can
actually affect people’s perspectives and actions. She may bring important
stories to American homes, but what if her stories about the plight of some
families remain simply too unrelatable for others? She feels that she needs to
do more. At one time, she thinks:  “Intellectually, I knew that I couldn’t do a
damn thing to change the situation in Syria anyway, no matter how many risks I
was willing to take. And yet I could not shake this oppressive feeling that I
was failing, that I wasn’t doing enough, that I was letting people down” (p.
269). One feeling she has is of futility. She laments her own limitations, that
she cannot solve an entire country’s problems. However, she also feels
personally inadequate. The combination of these feelings is crushing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her memoir, Clarissa Ward shares her insecurities regarding her positive
impact as a journalist. Ward often meets people in crisis, and struggles to
leave them while they continue to suffer emotionally, or continue to need some
tangible relief. She questions whether her reporting creates a greater good. The
suspicion that her words and actions are never enough discourages Ward. She
persists in her work, however, because: “…there is a shared human experience,
no matter how different our societies, that connects us. Perhaps this is why I
continue to feel such passion for my work, notwithstanding the frustrations and
limitations” (p. 313). Despite the challenges, Ward finds enough motivation from
her deep-seated compassion for others. Regardless of how satisfying the
outcomes, she consistently chooses to listen and share the voices of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ward, C. (2020). &lt;em&gt;On all fronts: The education of a journalist&lt;/em&gt;. Penguin Books.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="18+" /><summary type="html">In the 2020 memoir, On All Fronts, CNN’s chief international correspondent, Clarissa Ward, exhibits her perseverance throughout frustrating experiences that make her doubt her work. As a teenager, Clarissa Ward expresses her desire to help people: “I can understand people and convey their ideas. I’m a communicator” (p. 25). The desire to understand people and facilitate communication intensifies following the terrorist attacks in the United States on September 11, 2001, while Clarissa attends college. In the wake of the attacks, she relates: “I knew I had to go to the front lines, to hear the stories of people who lived there and tell them to the people back home” (p. 24). Clarissa Ward enters the field of journalism as a young adult, and during her career, travels around the world to listen to people and share their stories with the public. In her memoir, Clarissa Ward illustrates her persistence, despite recurring feelings of guilt regarding what she perceives as her emotional, material, and journalistic shortcomings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/on-all-fronts.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/on-all-fronts.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Arrietty the Teenage Borrower</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/03/03/the-borrowers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arrietty the Teenage Borrower" /><published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/03/03/the-borrowers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/03/03/the-borrowers.html">&lt;p&gt;Until the age of about thirteen, Arrietty Clock lives and communicates only with
her parents, Pod and Homily Clock. Author Mary Norton’s portrait of the Clock
family, the borrowing protagonists of the 1952 novel, &lt;em&gt;The Borrowers&lt;/em&gt;, depicts
relatable family life with a teenager. The Clock family’s teenage daughter,
Arrietty, begins to want more than what her loving parents have to offer her
within their comfortable home. In Mary Norton’s coming of age work, Arrietty
seeks increased physical freedom, knowledge, and relationships beyond the world
that she shares with her parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;arrietty-wants-knowledge&quot;&gt;Arrietty wants knowledge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a confined space, with only two other people, and limited resources, Arriety
senses that there is much she does not know. Furthermore, Arriety’s parents are
not always forthcoming. Pod and Homily sometimes refuse to offer satisfying
explanations, even for the occurrences they mention themselves. Her parents
often refer to the fate of Arriety’s young cousin, Eggletina, as a reason why
Arriety must not leave their home. Arriety presses them: “‘what,’ Eggletina
would ask, ‘did happen to Eggletina?’ But no one would ever say” (p. 13).
Arriety wants  information to better understand her extended family, and also
the thinking behind her parents’ expectations. Arriety’s parents do finally tell
her Eggletina’s story, and the dangers of the wider world, but they do not
lessen Arriety’s desire to go outside. When Arrietty does venture outside their
home, she makes a friend that helps her access even more knowledge. She and her
new friend spend much of their time with books. When her friend asks Arrietty to
read him one of her books, she tells him that she prefers to read new books (p.
127). Arrietty learns about the earth, and joyously shares her new information
with her parents. She asks them: “Did you know that the Arctic night lasts six
months, and that the distance between the two poles is less than that between
the two extremities of a diameter drawn through the equator?” (p. 133). Arrietty
fascinates herself with new geographic regions, and wonders at spatial
comparisons that help her comprehend the true size of the earth. Through the
books, Arrietty also learns more about herself: “She learned a lot and some of
the things she learned were hard to accept. She was made to realize once and for
all that this earth on which they lived turning about in space did not revolve,
as she had believed, for the sake of little people” (p. 132). Much of the new
information Arrietty discovers challenges her opinions. As her knowledge of the
world increases, her understanding of herself also changes. She comes to see
herself in a greater context, and becomes more humble. Despite the challenges,
the days she spends learning are “happy days to look back on afterwards” (p.
131). Over the course of the novel, Arrietty seeks and finally obtains more
information about herself, her family’s history, and the earth in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;arrietty-wants-freedom&quot;&gt;Arrietty wants freedom&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time that  Arrietty cries in Mary Norton’s novel is when the family
talks about a journey outdoors. Arrietty’s eyes fill with tears and she cries:
“I bet [Eggletina] just ran away because she hated being cooped up…day after
day…week after week…year after year…Like I do! Gates…gates, gates, gates…” (p.
49). Despite the comfort of her home, and the love she has for her parents, and
despite the dangers of the outside world, Arrietty yearns to go outdoors. She
can understand her cousin Eggeltina’s secret trip outside because Arrietty too
feels, “cooped up,” like a domestic animal. She thinks of the days, weeks, and
years that pass while she must stay in her home. The gates, which she is not
strong enough to open, are her barriers. After some further reasoning, Arriety’s
parents eventually agree that she may go outside and learn the ways of
borrowing. The first time Pod takes Arrietty out to borrow, Arrietty pushes the
boundaries: “Pod came again to the top of the step and looked along the path.
‘Don’t you go far,’ he said after a moment. Seeing his lips move, she smiled
back at him: she was too far already to hear the words’’ (p. 67). A visit
outside alongside her father is not enough for Arrietty. She wanders farther
away than her father intends for her, and feels no fear when she can no longer
hear him. After her first visit outside with her father, Arrietty endeavors to
sneak out on her own. While her father is out, she remembers that he keeps the
gates open as long as he is out. She realizes that during one of his outings is
her chance to escape as well: “Arrietty suddenly was sitting bolt upright: a
thought had struck her, leaving her breathless and a little shaky at the
knees…the gates would be open!” (p. 106). As if struck by lightning, her
attention is suddenly piqued. She is excited to the point of breathlessness and
shaking, and sees a chance which she takes. Arriety’s reactions are most extreme
regarding her physical freedom: She cries when she talks about her confinement
to the indoors, and feels such excitement at the thought of being outdoors  that
her emotions manifest  physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;arriety-wants-relationships&quot;&gt;Arriety wants relationships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no one besides her parents to talk to, Arriety sometimes chooses to share
her thoughts in a diary. One evening while her father is out and her mother is
busy with housework, Arrietty gets her diary. She, “…stared a moment, deep in
thought…She had kept [her diary] for nearly two years already, and today, 22nd
March, she read last year’s entry: “Mother’s cross.” She thought a while longer
then, at last, she put ditto marks under “mother,” and “worried” under ‘cross’”
(p. 22). The only other time Arrietty cries in the story, is when she thinks of
the possibility that she might be the last Borrower on earth one day. The first
chance she gets, Arriety tries to establish contact with her extended family.
She writes a letter to her Uncle Hendreary, her Aunt Lupy and her cousins, which
reads: “I hope you are quite well and the cousins are well and Aunt Lupy. We are
very well and I am learning to borrow…Write a letter on the back please” (p.
94). She writes to her extended family without her parents’ knowledge, and with
the simple desire to form bonds with other Borrowers. Arrietty also becomes
attached to the human boy in the big house. Once she meets him, she wants to
spend more time with him: “Arriety usually enjoyed this spring sorting…She used
to love turning over the scraps of silk or lace…But this year Arriety banged
about impatiently and stole away whenever she dared, to stare through the
grating, hoping to see the boy” (p. 96). Once she has a friend, Arriety’s
solitary pastimes no longer sustain her. Her preference is to spend time with
the boy. As a thirteen year old, Arrietty seeks more ways to express herself,
outside of her relationship with her parents. She writes in a diary, tries to be
friendly with her extended family, and pursues a friendship with another child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she enters her teenage years, young Arrietty Clock yearns to explore. She
seeks knowledge, experiences, and relationships that she cannot obtain from her
parents within their home. Arriety’s intellectual, physical, and interpersonal
curiosity arises not from any shortcomings of her parents or environment, but
from a natural progression. Arriety’s curiosity indicates the natural maturation
of a child towards adulthood. Happily for Arriety, her parents allow her to
venture further than her childhood home, and find the learning, wide world, and
friendships that she desires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Norton, M. (1952). &lt;em&gt;The Borrowers&lt;/em&gt;. Harcourt, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="13-15" /><summary type="html">Until the age of about thirteen, Arrietty Clock lives and communicates only with her parents, Pod and Homily Clock. Author Mary Norton’s portrait of the Clock family, the borrowing protagonists of the 1952 novel, The Borrowers, depicts relatable family life with a teenager. The Clock family’s teenage daughter, Arrietty, begins to want more than what her loving parents have to offer her within their comfortable home. In Mary Norton’s coming of age work, Arrietty seeks increased physical freedom, knowledge, and relationships beyond the world that she shares with her parents.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/the-borrowers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/the-borrowers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Buck Chooses the North over Man</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/02/16/the-call-of-the-wild.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Buck Chooses the North over Man" /><published>2022-02-16T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/02/16/the-call-of-the-wild</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2022/02/16/the-call-of-the-wild.html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Call of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; (1903), author Jack London creates a world that
challenges the supremacy of man. London portrays humans as animals like any
other, and  at the same time, consistently personifies dogs and nature in order
to highlight their complexity. From the perspective of the main character, the
dog Buck, humans are relatable but also expendable. When Buck ultimately sheds
the presence of humans in his life, the choice seems natural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;humans&quot;&gt;Humans&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half St. Bernard, half Scotch shepherd dog, Buck recognizes that just like dogs,
humans can have mixed ancestry. One of the first men in the North that Buck
respects is Francois,  “…a French-Canadian half-breed…” (p. 11). Another man
Buck encounters is a nameless “…Scotch half-breed…” (p. 45). Men consider the
breed of other men as well. When John Thornton meets Mercedes, Charles, and Hal,
he listens to them and decides that, “He knew the breed, and he gave his advice
in the certainty that it would not be followed” (p. 64). John Thornton believes
he knows the type of people that Mercedes, Charles, and Hal are. Their
individuality does not impress Thornton, and he believes that the family of three
has the same traits as the others of their kind. Humans, like all animals, come
from various stock, and  live by their instincts and reactions in a harsh world.
When he witnesses an injustice, for example, John Thornton seems to
instinctively intervene: “…suddenly, without warning, uttering a cry that was
inarticulate and more like the cry of an animal, John Thornton sprang upon the
man who wielded the club” (p. 66). John Thornton cries out &lt;em&gt;inarticulately&lt;/em&gt;,
like an &lt;em&gt;animal&lt;/em&gt;. He &lt;em&gt;springs&lt;/em&gt; upon his target, and uses the strength of his
body rather than a weapon to subdue his target. Buck attacks similarly, in the
manner of: “…an animal the like of which they had never seen before…a live
hurricane of fury, hurling himself upon them in a frenzy to destroy. He sprang
at the foremost man…” (p. 98).  Both Buck and John Thornton attack like animals,
and spring upon their enemies. The similarities of their attacks highlight the
comparable nature of men and dogs when they must fight and have only their own
bodies at their disposal. When Buck kills some men, he reasons: “He had killed
man, the noblest game of all…Thenceforward he would be unafraid of them…” (p.
100). Buck gives men credit for being the &lt;em&gt;noblest of all&lt;/em&gt;, but still
understands that man is &lt;em&gt;game&lt;/em&gt;, an animal he can hunt like any other. Once Buck
sees that he is able to kill humans, he no longer feels intimidated by them. In
London’s story, the breeds, bodies, and mortality of humans are unremarkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dogs&quot;&gt;Dogs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the characters in &lt;em&gt;The Call of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;, the dog Buck leads the most
interesting and varied life. Buck - not Judge Miller - is the king of their
family’s California property. A description of Buck’s home includes the claim
that “…over this great demesne Buck ruled…in right royal fashion. During the
four years since his puppyhood he had lived the life of a sated aristocrat; he
had a fine pride in himself, was even a trifle egotistical, as country gentlemen
sometimes become because of their situation” (p. 2-3). Buck spends his days like
an &lt;em&gt;aristocract&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;country gentleman&lt;/em&gt;, who wants for nothing. He &lt;em&gt;rules&lt;/em&gt;, in
the typical &lt;em&gt;royal&lt;/em&gt; manner, over the estate. His emotions are complicated, as he
is capable of feeling satisfaction, pride, and egotism. Indeed, Buck “…was
king, - king over all creeping, crawling, flying things of Judge Miller’s place,
humans included” (p. 3). Buck occupies the highest position of power and respect
on Judge Miller’s property - no human or animal ranks above him. In the Fall of
1897, however, Buck’s luck drastically changes. The “kidnapped king” (p. 5)
suddenly finds himself on a sled dog team in Dyea, Alaska. Between his more
seasoned colleagues, Dave and Sol-leks, Buck learns the new work: “Apt scholar
that he was, [Dave and Sol-leks] were equally apt teachers, never allowing him
to linger long in error, and enforcing their teaching with their sharp teeth”
(p. 20). In Alaska, the proud, egotistical king quickly becomes the novice
&lt;em&gt;scholar&lt;/em&gt; - in a new world where veteran sled dogs (the &lt;em&gt;teachers&lt;/em&gt;) wield power.
The work and environment invigorates Buck. His new duties consume him and he
soon rises to a position of power himself. At the head of a sled team in the
wild North, a certain kind of joy comes to Buck: “This ecstasy, this
forgetfulness of living, comes to the artist, caught up and out of himself in a
sheet of flame; it comes to the soldier, war-mad on a stricken field and
refusing quarter; and it came to Buck, leading the pack…” (p. 37). In his role
as sled team leader, Buck has the same experiences as dedicated human
professionals in their field. He reaches a place where he feels the same passion
as an &lt;em&gt;artist&lt;/em&gt;, and the same intensity as a &lt;em&gt;soldier&lt;/em&gt;. Throughout the adventure
of his life, Buck has similar experiences to kings, scholars, artists, and
soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;nature&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Buck, the “North” (p. 3), or Yukon, also comes to life as a vibrant
character. Soon after his kidnapping, Buck travels north to see the, “Chilcoot
Divide, which stands between the salt water and fresh and guards forbiddingly
the sad and lonely North” (p. 20). Upon his first encounter with the North, the
former king Buck seems to meet a king of the wild. On Buck’s property, “a legion
of housemaids armed with brooms and mops” (p. 2), stand guard. In the wild, the
Chilcoot Divide stands guard. The Divide initially stands between Buck and the
North, a character Buck comes to know as sad and lonely. Like Buck, the North
changes over time. In the Spring, “The Yukon was straining to break loose the
ice that bound it down. It ate away from beneath; the sun ate from above” (p.
64). The Yukon makes a great effort to escape the winter, and &lt;em&gt;eats&lt;/em&gt; the ice in
order to break free. Like a good friend, the sun assists the Yukon in its
endeavor. As the Yukon dissolves the ice, it seems to pay no attention to the
location of other living beings. One Spring, Buck observes humans and dogs on
the river ice when suddenly he sees, “…a whole section of ice give way and
dogs and humans disappear. A yawning hole was all that was to be seen” (p. 67).
The Yukon breaks free of winter, and, still sleepy, the Yukon &lt;em&gt;yawns&lt;/em&gt; in an
attempt to fully wake for the Spring. Like a giant that cannot be bothered by
insignificant creatures, the Yukon isn’t always aware of what it swallows. The
Yukon can, however, communicate effectively with these creatures when it so
desires. The Yukon communicates with Buck in order to alert him to a significant
event. As Buck traverses the wilderness, he senses that “…the very breeze
whispered of it. Several times [Buck] stopped and drew in the fresh morning air
in great sniffs, reading a message which made him leap on with greater speed”
(p. 97). The Yukon &lt;em&gt;whispers&lt;/em&gt; the news to Buck, and he in turn clearly
understands the urgent messages. In London’s world, the Yukon is moody and
powerful, yet subtle and communicative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A king in California, Buck becomes a lowly scholar, and eventually, with the
help of his canine teachers, a passionate professional in his field. As Buck is
able to adapt, so is the North - which adjusts according to the seasons. Both
Buck and the North exhibit emotion, nuance, and power. They both prove their
ability to overcome humans, who are no more dignified or strong than any other
presence on earth. In his novel, London humbles the race of men. He brings
attention to the significance of dogs and nature in the world. When Buck begins
to live a life among dogs in nature, without humans, Buck’s gains make the
absence of humans no great loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London, J. (2011). &lt;em&gt;The call of the wild&lt;/em&gt;. Collins Classics. (Original publication 1903).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="13-15" /><summary type="html">In The Call of the Wild (1903), author Jack London creates a world that challenges the supremacy of man. London portrays humans as animals like any other, and at the same time, consistently personifies dogs and nature in order to highlight their complexity. From the perspective of the main character, the dog Buck, humans are relatable but also expendable. When Buck ultimately sheds the presence of humans in his life, the choice seems natural.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/the-call-of-the-wild.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/the-call-of-the-wild.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Malcolm X and Judy Heumann Learn to Demand Justice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/18+/2022/01/24/malcolm-x-and-judy-heumann.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Malcolm X and Judy Heumann Learn to Demand Justice" /><published>2022-01-24T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2022-01-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/18+/2022/01/24/malcolm-x-and-judy-heumann</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/18+/2022/01/24/malcolm-x-and-judy-heumann.html">&lt;p&gt;Both Malcolm X (b. 1925) and Judy Heumann (b. 1947), grow up in a country that
tells them they are different, and undeserving of full participation in society.
Malcolm X’s work, &lt;em&gt;The Autobiography of Malcolm X&lt;/em&gt; (1965), and Judy Heumann’s
memoir, &lt;em&gt;Being Heumann&lt;/em&gt; (2020), show how years of socialization cause Malcolm and Judy to become accustomed to the dominant culture’s discrimination against people of color and people with disabilities, respectively. As young
adults, however, they begin to change again. Both Malcolm X and Judy Heumann
start to see that their marginalization is unjust, and that others like them
also suffer.  They begin to believe that American society can do better, and they
demand improvement. The lives of Malcolm X and Judy Heumann illustrate how individuals can be victims of their culture, and how they can institute positive change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm’s 8th grade English teacher, a white man named Mr. Ostrowski, asks
Malcom what sort of work he would like to do as an adult. When Malcolm tells Mr.
Ostrowski that he would like to be a lawyer, Mr. Ostrowski insists that a law
career is not a realistic goal for a black person. The exchange exposes Malcolm
to the dominant society’s view of him. He relates: “It was a surprising thing
that I had never thought of it that way before, but I realized that…apparently I
was still not intelligent enough, in their eyes, to become whatever &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; wanted
to be” (p. 44). The conversation Malcolm has with Mr. Ostrowski teaches him that
no matter how talented he is, or how hard he works, there is no expectation for
him to ever occupy a position of power in the community. Malcolm X recalls,
“That’s when I began to change - inside. I drew away from white people. I came
to class, and I answered when called upon. It became a physical strain simply to
sit in Mr. Ostrowski’s class” (p. 44). Malcolm begins to feel withdrawn and
unmotivated, not because of the color of his skin, but because of a respected
teacher’s low expectations of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a child, words of rejection also change Judy Heumann. One day, while in her
wheelchair on the sidewalk, a child she doesn’t know rudely asks her if she is
sick. She shares, “I saw myself through his eyes, and the light around me
shifted…It was the world and how it saw me. The world thought I was sick…I
wasn’t expected to be a part of the world” (p. 13). In one moment on the street,
Judy becomes painfully aware of how others judge her. Each experience of
exclusion thus far in her life suddenly makes sense. She feels: “I was a
butterfly, becoming a caterpillar…I was self-conscious now of feeling changed in
some unspeakable way I didn’t fully understand. After that day, nothing was ever
quite the same” (p. 13-14). Judy’s disability does not make her inherently
self-conscious. Instead, people’s consistent reactions to her finally convince
her that there is something wrong with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;messages&quot;&gt;Messages&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an all white school, Malcolm understands that the white people will tolerate
him and be friendly if he remains within the boundaries they designate.
Regarding coed situations at school, and specifically at school dances: “…I
could sense it almost as a physical barrier, that despite all the beaming and
smiling, the mascot wasn’t supposed to dance with any of the white girls. It was
some kind of psychic message…” (p. 36). The understanding he develops is that as
the only black boy (the mascot) at the school, he must not become too friendly
with the white girls at school. He explains how he regulates his behavior in response: “I would just stand around and
smile and talk and drink punch and eat sandwiches, and then I would make some
excuse and get away early…I had become fairly adept at avoiding the white girl
issue…” (p. 36 - 37). In his youth, Malcolm understands that his school
community expects him to feel grateful for the level of inclusion the school
offers him, and that he must not try to integrate himself completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Society sends a similar message to Judy Heumann, the girl who uses a wheelchair.
She understands that, “No one expected me to date. I was ‘crippled’ and was
often told, whether explicitly and implicitly, that no boy would ever give me a
second look” (p. 31). The message to Judy is that people without disabilities are not
romantically interested in people with disabilities. An boyfriend without a disability is not an
option and she seems not to dwell on the matter. Like Malcolm, Judy acts accordingly: “So in high school, I didn’t date. I talked
on the phone and studied.” (p. 32). Judy engages in ways that others communicate are
available and appropriate for her; she can speak to friends and work hard at
school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;acceptance&quot;&gt;Acceptance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a time in his life, Malcolm X lives with the common justification for the
segregation and degradation of black people. He reflects on his thinking at the time:
“Mine was the same psychology that makes Negroes even today, though it bothers
them down inside, keep letting the white man tell them how much ‘progress’ they
are making. They’ve heard it so much they’ve almost gotten brainwashed into
believing it - or at least accepting it” (p. 35). The dominant thinking in
society is that although marginalized, black people have far more privileges in 20th century America
than during slavery in 19th centruy America. The idea is that black people
should be satisfied with the reality that they are no longer enslaved, and
should continue to conform to the dominant white world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judy reflects on the many times in her life when she is unable to participate
because some program, form of transportation, or building is inaccessible. She
remembers a summer camp during her childhood specifically. The basement of the
camp is inaccessible to people who use wheelchairs. Judy’s parents agree that
Judy doesn’t have to be with the other children when they go to the basement
because they are grateful that Judy is able to attend the camp at all.
Judy explains, “…parents needed us kids to adjust and accept not participating
- and we learned to do this. We accepted that our inclusion was dependent on
someone else being ‘nice’” (p. 26). Judy and her family don’t want to ask for too much, to cause any problems, so they accept Judy’s exclusion for part of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;awakening&quot;&gt;Awakening&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1946, at the age of twenty, Malcolm X goes to prison. He begins to hear about
the teachings of Elijah Muhammad, and shares, “I still marvel at how swiftly my
previous life’s thinking pattern slid away from me, like snow off a roof…” (p.
196).  Elijah Muhammad teaches him to think of himself not just as an
individual, but as one of many black men in the context of racist America.
Malcolm X explains that Elijah Muhammad’s words, “…gave me something to think
about. The black prisoner, [Elijah Muhammad] said, symbolized white society’s
crime of keeping black men oppressed and deprived and ignorant, and unable to
get decent jobs, turning them into criminals” (p. 195). In prison, Malcom
studies American society and learns how groups of people are products not only
of their personal choices, but also their environments. When he leaves prison,
Malcolm X fights injustice in America for the rest of his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1970, the New York City Board of Education denies Judy Heumann (a qualified,
twenty-two-year-old college graduate) her teaching license on account of her
disability. She remembers of the event, “A dam had broken. After all this time,
all the years of being ignored and dismissed, I felt…an opportunity to call
attention and start to make it right” (p. 58). Judy Heumann begins to fight back
against the status quo. She feels that her exclusion from teaching is part of a
bigger problem. She thinks not only of herself, but, “…about all the people.
Yes, I did want to be a teacher, but in my mind, it was about all the stories
I’d heard about someone’s brother or sister, or their father, their mother,
their cousin, or they themselves—and how they had this problem or that problem
and no one was listening and things weren’t happening” (p. 58). The unjust
denial of her teaching license spurs Judy Heumann into action to defend the
rights of all people with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm X gains confidence in his cause during his travels to the Middle-East and Africa. He
insists, “But on this pilgrimage, what I have seen, and experienced, has forced
me to &lt;em&gt;re-arrange&lt;/em&gt; much of my thought-patterns previously held, and to toss
aside some of my previous conclusions” (p. 391). Malcolm X’s experiences in
countries such as Egypt and Saudi Arabia help him to see that not all societies
are like American society. Along the pilgrimage, he witnesses thousands of
pilgrims: “They were of all colors, from blue-eyed blonds to black-skinned
Africans. But we were all participating in the same ritual, displaying a spirit
of unity and brotherhood that my experiences in America had led me to believe
never could exist between the white and the non-white” (p. 390). Malcolm X sees
Muslims of all races practice their religion side by side. He sees that white
people and people of color can exist peacefully, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judy Heumann’s trip abroad also inspires her. She writes that her trip to
Europe, “…opened my eyes to the fact that how we did things in the US was not
the norm everywhere. My entire trip had a profound impact on me. It made me see
things in a different way than I had before” (p. 156). Judy Heumann sees that
other countries have different policies and practices than the United States.
She relates the effect of these different policies in action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Right away, it was the countries with universal healthcare that impressed me
the most, the way their concept of healthcare extended far beyond our idea
of healthcare…In some countries, housing authorities received money to work
with people to modify their houses or apartments and make them accessible,
whether they rented or owned…I got to learn about Sweden’s social welfare
system - and how it provided financial security, healthcare, and social
services, protecting Swedish society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judy Heumann becomes convinced that people with disabilities do not need to
lower their expectations in life. Instead, infrastructure and policies can
change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;demands&quot;&gt;Demands&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm X decides that in order to fight injustice, he must oppose specific
injustices. One night in Harlem, two white police officers break up an
altercation between black men. The police officers order passers-by to move
along, and when one witness - Johnson Hinton - stays by the scene, the police
beat him. Malcolm X and other members of the Nation of Islam learn of the
incicdent, go to the police station, and demand to see Johnson Hinton. Malcolm X
insists that Johnson Hinton go to the hospital. Malcolm X and the others follow
the ambulance along the streets and gather attention. That night, “The crowd was
big, and angry, behind the Muslims in front of Harlem Hospital. Harlem’s black
people were long since sick and tired of police brutality. And they never had
seen any organization of black men take a firm stand as we were” (p. 269).
As a grown man, Malcolm X sees that American society is flawed but also changeable, and
that he - not society - is the one worthy of acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Judy Heumann learns that too many people suffer because of exclusion, and
that life for these many people could be different, she begins to refuse the
state of society. She comes to understand that, “Inevitably, being ignored puts
you in the position of having to choose between making a fuss or accepting the
silent treatment. If you stand up to the ignorer and get in their face, you
break the norms of polite behavior…” (p. 143). Judy Heumann knows that society
does not want to change, because change can require effort and money. When human
rights are ignored, however, she knows that she must object loudly and take action that is impossible to ignore. She and several other activists go to the
Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW) to demand that Secretary
Califano sign the regulations for Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.
Guards at HEW deny the protestors entry to the building, so Judy Heumann fights
back. She remembers: “Then, I drove my chair directly toward the building. The
guards jumped to the side and watched me, frozen in total disbelief, as I
smashed into the door” (p. 142). After weeks of protest, Secretary Califano
signs the regulations into law, and Judy Heumann and her fellow activists
achieve their objective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born in 20th century America about twenty years apart, the lives of Malcolm X
and Judy Heumann follow the same journey of acculturation, then resistance.
American society teaches Malcolm X that he is not an equal citizen because he is black. The same society teaches Judy Heumann she cannot fully
participate because of her physical disability. Although American society is
flawed, the society deems Malcolm X and Judy Heumann, and many others like them,
as the flawed ones. Disparaging views of people of color and people with
disabilities are so pervasive, that even those people who are excluded from
society come to accept the views. Despite society’s efforts, however, Malcolm X
and Judy Heumann ultimately return to their original instinct that they are no
less than anyone else. They challenge the United States to evolve and to
broaden the nation’s narrow understanding of the deserving human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heumann, J. &amp;amp; Joiner, K. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Being Heumann: An unrepentant memoir of a
disability rights activist.&lt;/em&gt; Beacon Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haley, A. &amp;amp; X, M. (1964). &lt;em&gt;The autobiography of Malcolm X&lt;/em&gt;. The Random House
Publishing Group.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="18+" /><summary type="html">Both Malcolm X (b. 1925) and Judy Heumann (b. 1947), grow up in a country that tells them they are different, and undeserving of full participation in society. Malcolm X’s work, The Autobiography of Malcolm X (1965), and Judy Heumann’s memoir, Being Heumann (2020), show how years of socialization cause Malcolm and Judy to become accustomed to the dominant culture’s discrimination against people of color and people with disabilities, respectively. As young adults, however, they begin to change again. Both Malcolm X and Judy Heumann start to see that their marginalization is unjust, and that others like them also suffer. They begin to believe that American society can do better, and they demand improvement. The lives of Malcolm X and Judy Heumann illustrate how individuals can be victims of their culture, and how they can institute positive change.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/malcolm-x-and-judy-heumann.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/malcolm-x-and-judy-heumann.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Make a Character Chart for _Legendborn_</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/16-18/2021/12/15/legendborn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make a Character Chart for _Legendborn_" /><published>2021-12-15T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-12-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/16-18/2021/12/15/legendborn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/16-18/2021/12/15/legendborn.html">&lt;p&gt;Tracy Deonn’s &lt;em&gt;Legendborn&lt;/em&gt; (2020), follows Briana Matthews as she meets a full cast of complex characters. Most of the characters are around the same age and attend the University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill. The new people that Briana comes to know exhibit various backgrounds, physical traits, preferences, and behaviors. A simple character chart can help track each character’s development. The character chart below includes descriptions, as well as the words and actions of ten of the new people that Briana meets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;main id=&quot;legendborn-characters&quot;&gt;
  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #178DE9&quot;&gt;Victoria (Tor) Morgan, Scion of Sir Tristan&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“A tall blond girl scowls...She’s beautiful the way a well-maintained dagger is beautiful: sharp, shiny, and all angles. A bit prissy. Absolutely Alice’s type” - Briana (p. 18)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Victoria Morgan. Goes by Tor. A serious legacy...Her daddy and granddaddy and whoever else all the way back to whenever went to UNC. Couple years ago, her fam donated so much $ to the B School they renamed a building after them. Old money good ol’ boys’” - Charlotte (p. 47)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Victoria is the Scion of the Line of Tristan, third-ranked, with Sarah as her squire... Marksmanship and speed’” - William (p. 137)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Yea, that was Tor’s rebellious phase. I think she did it just to piss her parents off...Dating a Merlin would piss any Legendborn parent off’” - Sarah (p. 335)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #CC0000&quot;&gt;Felicity Caldwell, Scion of Sir Lamorak&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“A curvy, short girl with wavy red hair…” - Briana (p. 88)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘...Felicity is a Scion, born with the title like me…’” - Nick (p. 89)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Felicity is the Scion of Lamorak’s bloodline. Ranked fourth, as you know. She chose Russ as her Squire in last year’s tournament. After tonight, she’ll be strong enough to punch through a boulder…’” - William (p. 137)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #F3CF0C&quot;&gt;Peter (Pete) Hood, Scion of Sir Owain&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I don’t know Pete at all, but I know he’s new, and kind” - Briana (p. 258)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I, Peter Herbert Hood, Scion of Sir Owain, seventh ranked, select Page Taylor as my Squire. With their agreement, we will be bonded. For this war and beyond” - Peter (p. 413)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #F08A2F&quot;&gt;Fitzsimmons (Fitz) Baldwin, Scion of Sir Bors&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Fitz looks like he’s considering clobbering me” - Briana (p. 95)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Fitz is the Scion of Sir Bors, eleventh ranked. In combat, he has agility like you’ve never seen. When we take a Squire, we’re choosing a battle partner to join us in the Warrior’s Oath. Someone who will share our bloodline’s power. Fitz chose Evan as his Squire last year’” - William (p. 137)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Fitz’s way - his entire family’s way - is...dishonorable’” - William (p. 138)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“...I see Fitz, cracking his knuckles like a prized fighter about to go in the ring” - Briana (p. 413)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #00FF00&quot;&gt;William Sitterson, Scion of Sir Gawain&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“...healer. Someone who helped me even though he doesn’t know my name” - Briana (p. 61)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The infirmary is William’s domain. He strides between the tables, his hands coated in silver aether so thick it looks like mercury. The bright, citrus smell of his aether signature fills the room” - Briana (p. 123)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“William regards me with unreadable gray eyes” - Briana (p. 129)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“I’m beginning to understand why Sel didn’t fight William’s will. He’s imperious without being arrogant, and has an uncanny knack for being right” - Briana (p. 133)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘I’m the Scion of the Line of Sir Gawain, twelfth-ranked. In addition to enhanced healing, the Spell gave Gawain preternatural strength at midday and midnight...Gawain was an odd guy, what can I say’” - William (p. 137)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“William runs a hand through his light hair and releases a long sigh” - Briana (p. 243)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘I, William Jeffrey Sitterson, Scion of Sir Gawain, twelfth-ranked, select Page Whitlock as my Squire’” - William (p. 413)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #178DE9;&quot;&gt;Sarah, Tor’s Squire&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“...a pixielike girl with short dark hair...large dark eyes…” - Briana (p. 76)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Sarah steps forward...I’m surprised by her defense of me, someone she doesn’t know” - Briana (p. 125).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Can I drive you home?’” - Sarah (p. 143)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘[My dad] is Venezuelan. But I pass, so people don’t realize I am too. Or they forget. They say racist crap around me sometimes...Sometimes I check ‘em. Sometimes I don’t bother’” - Sarah (p. 144)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Sel takes three determined strides toward me before Sarah slides between us. Even though the Merlin is the superior opponent with a foot of height on her, the pint-size girl glares up at him poised for a fight. The steel in her eyes tells me she’d put up a good one” - Briana (p. 145)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Back off Sel, I’m taking Bree to her dorm’” - Sarah (p. 146)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #CC0000&quot;&gt;Russ Copeland, Felicity’s Squire&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“...a tall, lanky boy with cropped brown hair...his jeans and wrinkled button-down shirt look like he’d plucked them from a sad pile of clothes on the floor” - Briana (p. 88)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“His mischievous eyes immediately put me at ease” - Briana (p. 89)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“...he brought me down to the infirmary...he came down to wait with me and offered me a sweatshirt” - Briana (p. 129, 124)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Then Russ jumps to his feet and whoops, triggering a wave of shouts and applause” - Briana (p. 331)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #F3CF0C&quot;&gt;Greer Taylor, Pete’s Squire&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“They’re basketball-player tall and lean, with long, muscled arms and legs. Their dirty-blond hair lies in a single braid over their shoulder, while a few shorter strands fall out the front of their slouchy gray knit cap. An unbuttoned, expensive-looking, slate-colored suit vest over an untucked denim shirt and cuffed jeans puts their look somewhere between designer and hipster. They’re also wringing their hands in front of their belt buckle in a nervous gesture that reminds me painfully of Alice” - Briana (p. 93)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Greer assesses me with their brown eyes and kind smile before stuffing another piece of gum in their mouth” - Briana (p. 94)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘People say shit about me, too. But my parents are major donors. I come from six generations of Vassal service and three generations of Pages, and I’m white, so they get strategic about when and where. Some folks just don’t care to get better or learn more, and it shows’” - Greer (p. 100)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Greer shoots me a look of genuine apology...” - Briana (p. 258)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #F08A2F&quot;&gt;Evan Cooper, Fitz’s Squire&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“...the tall red-haired boy…” - Briana (p. 12)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Hey, hey...Let’s not bring drama to the dinner table” - Evan (p. 404)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;

  &lt;section&gt;
    &lt;h1 style=&quot;background-color: #00FF00&quot;&gt;James (Whitty) Whitlock, William’s Squire&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“He has a stocky build with wild, pale curly hair, and he’s wearing a worn camo jacket and jeans. While the other kids are dressed for classes or the formality of the Lodge, Whitty’d look equally at home on a tractor or up a hunting blind. His casual indifference appeals to me immediately…” - Briana (p. 92)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘The Whitlocks are Vassals to the Line of Tristan, and they own most of the pig farms out in Clinton’” - Nick (p. 92)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Thought we’d come over and introduce ourselves’” - Whitty (p. 93)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“‘Put your knife down Schaefer.’ Whitty’s usually slow drawl is low with warning. ‘Nick can spend time talkin’ to his Page. Ain’t no harm there’” - Whitty (p. 184)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deonn, T. (2020). &lt;em&gt;Legendborn&lt;/em&gt;. Margaret K. McElderry Books.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="16-18" /><summary type="html">Tracy Deonn’s Legendborn (2020), follows Briana Matthews as she meets a full cast of complex characters. Most of the characters are around the same age and attend the University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill. The new people that Briana comes to know exhibit various backgrounds, physical traits, preferences, and behaviors. A simple character chart can help track each character’s development. The character chart below includes descriptions, as well as the words and actions of ten of the new people that Briana meets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/legendborn.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/legendborn.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Omar Mohamed’s Important Choices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/10-12/2021/12/01/when-the-stars-are-scattered.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Omar Mohamed’s Important Choices" /><published>2021-12-01T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/10-12/2021/12/01/when-the-stars-are-scattered</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/10-12/2021/12/01/when-the-stars-are-scattered.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When the Stars are Scattered&lt;/em&gt; (2020), by Victoria Jamieson and Omar Mohamed,
relates Omar’s experiences and the choices he makes in a refugee camp as a
child. When violence threatens their lives in Somalia, Omar and his younger
brother Hassan flee to Ifo, a refugee camp in Kenya, and one of the largest in
the world. For years, Omar and Hassan, who is nonverbal, live in a tent alone.
Without his parents, Omar must choose his friends, role models, and his own
self-talk carefully. Omar chooses to spend time with friends that accept his
brother as well, chooses to listen to adults that support his education, and
chooses to focus on gratitude instead of resentment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;omar-spends-time-with-peers-that-include-his-brother&quot;&gt;Omar spends time with peers that include his brother&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Omar’s brother, Hassan, does endure unkindness from some other children,
Omar carefully selects the people with whom they spend the most time. One boy,
Ali, lives near the brothers, and disparages Hassan. When Hassan doesn’t
understand a game the boys play, Ali says to Omar: “I don’t know why you bother
taking care of this moron! He’s a waste of space. You should let him wander off
into the bush to get eaten by lions! Now I know why you’re orphans. That’s
probably why your mom left you…” (p. 77). Ali calls Hassan names, says Hassan is
worthless, that Omar should leave Hassan to die, and that Omar’s mother doesn’t
want to be with her children because of Hassan’s disability. Ali’s cruel
behavior upsets both the brothers. Fortunately, the boys spend more time with
friends that know better. Jeri, who has a disability of his own, explains to
Omar that Hassan isn’t helpless. Jeri says: “There are lots of things [Hassan] can
do, even with a disability…He takes care of animals, and he helps your
neighbors…don’t underestimate him” (p. 80). Jeri defends Hassan and insists
that Hassan is a meaningful member of their community. He highlights how helpful
and kind Hassan is to people and animals. Another friend, Maryam, assures Omar:
“You’re not the only one who cares for [Hassan]…” and “[Hassan is] more
capable than you think he is” (p. 107). Maryam cares for Hassan and believes in
him. When Hassan is younger, Maryam looks after him in the afternoons. When he
is older, Maryam trusts Hassan to help her care for her own children. As a young
mother, Maryam is “… especially grateful for [Hassan’s] help…Hassan is very
attentive to little Nimo, and he loves playing with her” (p. 224). Maryam
includes Hassan in her life and treats him like a member of her own family.
Although there are times when other children such as Ali treat Hassan badly,
Hassan receives far more consistent support from Omar’s friends such as Jeri and
Maryam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;omar-listens-to-adults-that-encourage-his-education&quot;&gt;Omar listens to adults that encourage his education&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all the adults in Ifo see the value of an education, but Omar chooses to
take the advice of the adults that encourage him to go to school. When Omar and
his friends see Jeri’s father, the children tell him about what they want to be
when they grow up. Jeri’s father says, “I can tell you what you’ll be - you’ll
be a refugee…Us refugees, we are nothing but slave labor around here…You’re
in a prison right now. A giant, sprawling prison - and you’ll spend the rest of
your life here” (p. 127-128). Jeri’s father tells the young students that they
are refugees in a prison, that they can not make decent money with any job in
the camp, and that they will never leave the camp. His perspective is hopeless.
Thankfully, other adults in Omar’s life encourage him. Omar’s foster mother in
the refugee camp, Fatuma, reassures Omar, “We never know what will happen in our
lives…So stay in school. Prepare yourself and educate yourself, so you can be
ready…life is only a prison if you make it one” (p. 129-130). Despite Fatuma’s
many profound losses, Fatuma encourages Omar to have hope and to apply himself
to his studies. The Spanish social worker, Susana Martinez, also encourages Omar
and his classmates. She tells Omar’s class: “You are all strong, resilient
children, and I see so much potential in this room. I hope you’ll keep up with
your studies. If you have any problems - at home, or at school - you can always
talk to a UN officer. We are here to help” (p. 155). Susana Martinez tells Omar
and his peers that they impress her, and that they can come to her if they need
help. Later, she does help Omar when she buys him the new uniform he needs for
high school. Instead of adults like Jeri’s father, Omar chooses to listen to
adults such as Fatuma and Susana Martinez, who say that if he perseveres as a
hopeful, hardworking student, he can be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;omar-focuses-on-positive-thinking&quot;&gt;Omar focuses on positive thinking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are times when Omar resents his situation, but more often, Omar thinks
positive thoughts and focuses on the people he appreciates. When Omar can’t
sleep one night, he thinks about his uncomfortable sleeping mat, and the reality
that he may never be able to leave the refugee camp. He muses: “Why do some kids
have everything, and I have nothing? It’s not fair” (p. 137). After one
particularly difficult incident, however, Omar takes stock of his life. He
relates, “I don’t know if it’s praying…but I drift off to sleep staring at my
brother, and I thank God for all the good things we have” (p. 109). While
negative thoughts keep Omar awake at night, he finds that when he thinks
positive thoughts, he is able to fall asleep peacefully. Omar is grateful for
his life with his brother, Hassan, his closest relative and the person he sleeps
beside each night. Omar also appreciates his best friend in Ifo. He thinks, “I’m
thankful for Jeri. At least we are here together. We’ll always have each other’s
back” (p. 231). Jeri and Omar spend much of their time together, and Jeri often
defends and encourages his friend (p. 23, 41). Omar knows he can rely on Jeri.
Besides Jeri, Omar knows there are other people in Ifo that support him and his
brother. He reminds himself: “I am lucky. So many people love and support me and
Hassan. Fatuma, Salan, Maryam, Jeri, all of our neighbors. I can have faith in
my community…We may be refugees and orphans, but we are not alone” (p. 111).
Fatuma cares for Omar and Hassan in place of their parents. Salan organizes for
Omar to attend school and private English lessons. Maryam also encourages Omar
to go to school, and helps care for Hassan. When Omar thinks of his brother, his
best friend, and the support he receives from his community, he feels grateful
for what he has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omar spends over a decade in the Ifo refugee camp, where he must serve as the
head of a two person family. Much of what happens in Omar’s life, he cannot
control. However, Omar’s story shows that even in the most dire situations,
people always have choices. As he is responsible for his life and his brother’s,
Omar’s choices determine the present and future quality of their lives. Omar
chooses inclusive friends, decides to trust hopeful adults, and fills his mind
with gratitude in order to establish a good life for himself and Hassan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamieson, V. &amp;amp; Mohamed, O. (2020). &lt;em&gt;When the stars are scattered&lt;/em&gt;. Dial Books
for Young Readers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="10-12" /><summary type="html">When the Stars are Scattered (2020), by Victoria Jamieson and Omar Mohamed, relates Omar’s experiences and the choices he makes in a refugee camp as a child. When violence threatens their lives in Somalia, Omar and his younger brother Hassan flee to Ifo, a refugee camp in Kenya, and one of the largest in the world. For years, Omar and Hassan, who is nonverbal, live in a tent alone. Without his parents, Omar must choose his friends, role models, and his own self-talk carefully. Omar chooses to spend time with friends that accept his brother as well, chooses to listen to adults that support his education, and chooses to focus on gratitude instead of resentment.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/when-the-stars-are-scattered.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/when-the-stars-are-scattered.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Intersectionality and the Challenges of Rebellion in 18th Century Saint-Domingue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/16-18/2021/11/23/toussaint-louverture.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intersectionality and the Challenges of Rebellion in 18th Century Saint-Domingue" /><published>2021-11-23T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-11-23T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/16-18/2021/11/23/toussaint-louverture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/16-18/2021/11/23/toussaint-louverture.html">&lt;p&gt;In his 2016 biography, &lt;em&gt;Toussaint Louverture: A Revolutionary Life&lt;/em&gt;, author
Philippe Girard discusses the challenges of the slavery based society that rebels such as
Toussaint Louverture must navigate in 18th century Saint-Domingue (present day
Haiti). Toussaint Louverture’s parents are from Africa, but he is born enslaved
on the Breda family plantation of Haut-du-Cap, in the French colony of
Saint-Domingue. Although he obtains his freedom sometime before the Haitian
rebellion, the circumstances of Louverture’s manumission are unclear. Beginning
in 1791, Louverture plays a lead role in the rebellion against the
planter-enslavers on the island. Author Philippe Girard shows how the
complicated and deliberately divisive hierarchies of freedom, race, and culture
(and the combinations of these hierarchies) within the oppressed community, make
revolution on the island such a difficult endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;free&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Saint-Domingue, not all families of color are enslaved. Some families of
color come from generations of free folk, possess inherited or accumulated
wealth, and even enslave other people of color. Girard writes that these
families often “…were not rebels…[they] wanted to get rich the same way every
white Frenchman wanted to get rich: by buying and exploiting slaves” (p. 66). As
some families of color have more opportunities than the enslaved people on the
island, not all these families of color are inclined to support the rebellion.
When the enslaved people in Saint-Domingue begin their rebellion in 1791, white
planters are greatly outnumbered by the enslaved population. White planters
turn to free people of color to help them. The white planters, “…struck an
alliance with free men of color…[and] grudgingly granted free people of color
the political rights they had been requesting since 1789 in exchange for their
military assistance” (p. 116). In 1792, France declares that free people of
color are equal to white people under French law, which incentivizes many free
men of color even more to defend the white planters during the rebellion. The
free people of color that have their freedom before the rebellion become the
untrustworthy “formerly free,” people to the enslaved rebels who consider
themselves the “newly free.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;maroon&quot;&gt;Maroon&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other people of color in Saint-Domingue are not legally liberated, but live
in fugitive communities. Girard writes, “Short of outright revolt, the most
effective form of resistance was to become a maroon, a term derived from the
Spanish word for a wild animal (cimarron) that was used to describe slave
runaways” (p. 37). Some people who escape live permanently on independent
settlements. Others leave only temporarily, as a strike, until the plantation
owners or managers meet some term. As Girard explains of the enslaved people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They hailed from a world in which slavery was an established part of life on
both sides of the Atlantic, so imagining that free labor could be the norm
would have required a complete change of paradigm. In Haut-du-Cap, slaves
did not flee their plantations to bring slavery to its knees - a ludicrous
and even unthinkable idea at the time - but to protest excessive punishments
or the lack of food. They then returned to work after they had obtained what
they sought. p. 39.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “maroons” that live in various communities around the island are accustomed
to smaller-scale negotiations with plantation owners and managers. They have
their own agendas, and usually make what they believe to be reasonable demands
regarding their working conditions. At the outbreak of the Haitian revolution, a
complete overthrow of the system seems unlikely. Not all fugitive community
members want to align with such a drastic rebellion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mixed-race&quot;&gt;Mixed-Race&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with white and black people, 18th century Saint-Domingue harbors
mixed-race people of various racial backgrounds. Regarding the people of color
on the island: “Some were the mixed-race descendants of white colonists whose
skin color was described by a rich racial vocabulary, ranging from mulâtre
(mulatto) to quarteron (quadroon) and métif (octoroon)…” (p. 56). The term
“mulatto” refers to a person with one black parent and one white parent, while
“quadroon,” indicates a person who has one black grandparent and three white
grandparents. An “octoroon,” means someone with one black great-grandparent and
seven white great-grandparents. In the decades before the Saint-Domingue
rebellion, French authorities begin to require a person’s precise racial
background to appear on legal documents. On the basis of race, authorities deny
people of color social options. The stoked divisions among the racial groups
continue during the rebellion years. Factions of mixed-race, white, or black
people change allegiances and struggle for control of the colony. Girard writes
that of the: “Mixed-race officers like Rigaud, [white] French administrators
like Laveaux, the [black] “newly free” majority - who would prevail was an open
question” (p. 165). The emergence of black factions and mixed-race factions reflects the mistrut, instead of unification on the basis of race, among the people of color on the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;african-born&quot;&gt;African-born&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girard explains that in Saint-Domingue, the majority of enslaved people are from
Africa. Wealthy French men view the colony as a place to have a business, not as
a place to make home. Thus, the French population remains small, while the
enslaved population continues to grow. With the island’s demand for labor, a low
birth rate and high death rate (life expectancy on the Breda plantations is
thirty-seven), Saint-Domingue planters increase the number of people they
enslave from Africa. The number of enslaved people from Africa eventually totals
more than 900,000. Girard points out that “Sixty-four percent of Haut-du-Cap’s
slaves were African-born by 1785…As a result, many of the slaves of
Haut-du-Cap had only been in Saint-Domingue for a few years by the time the
Haitian Revolution began in 1791” (p. 49). The majority of enslaved people that
fight for freedom do so on foreign land, among foreign people (Europeans,
Carribbeans, and people from different African communities), and among foreign
languages and customs. Stratified Saint-Domingue society pushes African culture
and people to the bottom. Girard claims of the cultural hierarchy: “The chain of
contempt ended with the newly imported slaves, the bossales, a term derived from
the Spanish &lt;em&gt;bozales&lt;/em&gt; (muzzled, or shackled), but that was often rendered in
French as &lt;em&gt;peau sale&lt;/em&gt; (dirty skin)” (p. 68). Before the revolution, the
African-born people are the furthest from full participation in society and have
the fewest privileges. This most brutalized group of people must provide the most man power for the rebellion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;caribbean-born&quot;&gt;Caribbean-born&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only about a third of the enslaved population in the colony are Creole (born in
Saint-Domingue), like Louverture. Girard writes: “Surrounded by African-born slaves forcibly
brought to Saint-Domingue and European planters longing for France, Creoles
(Caribbean natives) like Louverture came to think of themselves as the only true
‘Americans’” (p. 26). Influenced by Africa, Europe, and the
Caribbean, the Saint-Domingue Creoles develop their own language (Haitian
Creole), and culture. Creoles also differ from Africans in the jobs that the
enslavers generally allow them to occupy on the plantations. In wake of the
rebellion, African-born people wonder if rebel Creole leaders like Louverture seek to
abolish slavery on the island or if they simply intend to take the places of the
white men. The mistrust reflects “…the rivalries that had pitted African born
field hands against Caribbean-born skilled workers on prerevolutionary
plantations. The African-born freedmen…had the nagging suspicion that the
creole elite and the formerly free had used them…” (p. 198). The preferential treatment of the Creoles by the European planters creates a division between the Creole and African-born enslaved people that persists during and after the rebellion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philippe Girard highlights the social nuances of Saint-Domingue in order to show
that when the rebellion commences, the conflict is not simply between the
minority rich, white, enslavers and a unified majority of enslaved, black
people; a simple binary that favors the oppressed does not exist. Girard
explains that French practices on the island before the rebellion create
deliberate hierarchies that divide the majority of disenfranchised people of
color into subgroups. The hierarchies of privilege complicate
a unified resistance against the European planters. Some free people of color
stand to gain if they side with French planters during the rebellion. Other
“runaway” people of color risk their small victories if they join a rebellion
that fails. Furthermore, people of color with disparate racial backgrounds, and
African-born and Creole people must overcome the French-imposed animosity
amongst themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-span.org/video/?451340-1/toussaint-louverture&quot;&gt;Listen to Professor Girard explain the Haitain Revolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Girard, P. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Toussaint Louverture: A revolutionary life&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="16-18" /><summary type="html">In his 2016 biography, Toussaint Louverture: A Revolutionary Life, author Philippe Girard discusses the challenges of the slavery based society that rebels such as Toussaint Louverture must navigate in 18th century Saint-Domingue (present day Haiti). Toussaint Louverture’s parents are from Africa, but he is born enslaved on the Breda family plantation of Haut-du-Cap, in the French colony of Saint-Domingue. Although he obtains his freedom sometime before the Haitian rebellion, the circumstances of Louverture’s manumission are unclear. Beginning in 1791, Louverture plays a lead role in the rebellion against the planter-enslavers on the island. Author Philippe Girard shows how the complicated and deliberately divisive hierarchies of freedom, race, and culture (and the combinations of these hierarchies) within the oppressed community, make revolution on the island such a difficult endeavor.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/toussaint.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/toussaint.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oppression Persists</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/18+/2021/11/01/persepolis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oppression Persists" /><published>2021-11-01T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/18+/2021/11/01/persepolis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/18+/2021/11/01/persepolis.html">&lt;p&gt;Born in 1969, Marjane Satrapi is about ten years old when the Islamic republic
replaces the Pahlavi dynasty in Iran. In her 2003 graphic novel, &lt;em&gt;Persepolis&lt;/em&gt;,
Marjane Satrapi recounts the fall and exile of the last Shah of Iran, and the
rise of the Islamic republic. Marjane’s family protests against the Shah, and
after the 1979 revolution, the family also protests against the Islamic
republic. The change in power from the royal family to the republic does not
bring the social justice that the Satrapis and many others seek. Through
Marjane’s eyes, divisions in social class, absolute power, and violence remain
the same before and after the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;divisions-in-social-class&quot;&gt;Divisions in Social Class&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a little girl, Marjane observes stark differences between the social classes.
Marjane shares of her family’s maid, Mehri: “like most peasants, she didn’t know
how to read and write…” (p. 35). In 1978, when Mehri falls in love with the
Satrapis’ neighbor, the adults involved quickly end the connection. Marjane’s
father explains to Marjane, “You must understand that their love was impossible.
Because in this country you must stay within your own social class” (p. 37).
Marjane and many of her family members despise the division between rich and
poor. Marjane’s grandfather expresses: “It disgusts me that people are condemned
to a bleak future by their social class” (p. 23). Marjane’s uncle, Anoosh, hopes
that one day, “The proletariat shall rule! It’s inevitable!” (p. 62). Marjane
understands, “The reason for my shame and for the revolution is the same: the
difference between social classes” (p. 33). Following the overthrow of the Shah,
however, the poor remain disempowered. Marjane’s family maid after the
revolution, Mrs. Nasrine, worries when the Islamic republic recruits her
fourteen-year-old son for service. Marjane’s cousin, Shahab, confirms of the
Iranian military, “It’s awful. Every day I see buses full of kids arriving. They
come from the poor areas, you can tell…first they convince them that the
afterlife is even better than disneyland…they hypnotize them and just toss
them into battle. Absolute carnage” (p. 101). The Islamic regime uses poor,
vulnerable young men to fight. Under the Shah, and the Islamic republic, there
exists a marginalized class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;absolute-power&quot;&gt;Absolute Power&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marjane’s father tells her about the events surrounding Reza Shah Pahlavi’s rise
to power. He tells her, “At the time, your grandpa was a young man and the
father of the Shah confiscated everything he owned” (p. 23). With the support of
the British government, Reza Shah Pahlavi seems to have the power to do whatever
he likes. After the 1979 revolution, Marjane and her family continue to feel the
pressures of an all powerful government. The new Islamic regime begins to
control every aspect of life. Marjane remembers: “And then suddenly in 1980…‘all
bilingual schools must be closed down. They are symbols of capitalism. Of
decadence’”(p. 4). Marjane can no longer attend her French, non-religious school
for boys and girls. The regime also judges what is appropriate to wear. Marjane
explains, “Then came 1980: The year it became obligatory to wear the veil at
school. We didn’t really like to wear the veil, especially since we didn’t
understand why we had to” (p. 3). Marjane and other women and girls must adhere
to the government’s social rules. Marjane experiences firsthand the:
“…guardians of the revolution, the women’s branch. This group had been added
in 1982, to arrest women who were improperly veiled. (Like me, for example)” (p.
132). Even as a child, if Marjane doesn’t dress according to the regime’s
standards, the authorities have the power to detain her indefinitely. The
Islamic regime strictly enforces the new expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;violence&quot;&gt;Violence&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the royal family, Marjane’s parents tell her that her grandfather, “…was
often sent to prison. Sometimes they put him in a cell filled with water for
hours…The poor man! Prison had destroyed his health” (p. 24-25). Marjane’s
grandfather endures torture while the royal family rules. Marjane and her family
protest the Shah’s rule, but face violence when they do. One day which people
come to know as Black Friday: “…there were so many killed in one of the
neighborhoods that a rumor spread that Israeli soldiers were responsible for the
slaughter. But in fact it was really our own who had attacked us. After Black
Friday, there was one massacre after another. Many people were killed” (p. 39).
The Satrapis risk their lives to oppose the Shah of Iran. However, with the new
Islamic regime, they remain in danger. A year after the 1979 revolution,
Marjane’s parents bring her with them to a demonstration against fundamentalism.
Marjane remembers: “I passed out flyers…when suddenly things got nasty. For
the first time in my life, I saw violence with my own eyes. That was our last
demonstration” (p. 76). Under the royal family and the Islamic republic,
protesters fear for their lives. The republic begins to target specific people,
and executes Marjane’s uncle, Anoosh. Marjane shares: “My uncle was imprisoned
by the Shah’s regime, but it was the Islamic regime that ordered his
execution…we’ve gone from 3,000 prisoners under the Shah to 300,000 prisoners
under [the Islamic] regime” (p. 144). Marjane sees how both the Shah and the
republic torture and kill people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marjane Satrapi and her family experience the repressive rule of one form of
government and then another. While rule changes from the Shah to the Islamic
republic, many of the problems remain the same. Under the Shah, Marjane and her
family members call for a more egalitarian society. With the fall of the Shah,
however, the family does not see a significant expansion of opportunity for the
oppressed. In fact, power remains in the tight control of the government. Under
both regimes, Marjane and her family are at the mercy of the government
regarding property, education, and even dress. Worst of all, the Satrapi family
learns that opposition to either government may result in torture and murder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satrapi, M. (2003). &lt;em&gt;Persepolis: The story of a childhood&lt;/em&gt;. Pantheon Books.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="18+" /><summary type="html">Born in 1969, Marjane Satrapi is about ten years old when the Islamic republic replaces the Pahlavi dynasty in Iran. In her 2003 graphic novel, Persepolis, Marjane Satrapi recounts the fall and exile of the last Shah of Iran, and the rise of the Islamic republic. Marjane’s family protests against the Shah, and after the 1979 revolution, the family also protests against the Islamic republic. The change in power from the royal family to the republic does not bring the social justice that the Satrapis and many others seek. Through Marjane’s eyes, divisions in social class, absolute power, and violence remain the same before and after the revolution.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/persepolis.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/persepolis.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">John Lewis: How a Young Person can Change the World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2021/10/29/march-book-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="John Lewis: How a Young Person can Change the World" /><published>2021-10-29T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2021-10-29T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/13-15/2021/10/29/march-book-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/13-15/2021/10/29/march-book-1.html">&lt;p&gt;The graphic novel, &lt;em&gt;March: Book One&lt;/em&gt; (2013), by Congressman John Lewis, Andrew
Aydin, and artist Nate Powell, shares how John Lewis’s productive behaviors as a
young man allows him to be an effective force of change even in his school
years. Born in Alabama in 1940, John Lewis plays a key role in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/event/American-civil-rights-movement&quot;&gt;American
civil rights
movement&lt;/a&gt;. As a
young person, John Lewis observes and thinks carefully about his surroundings,
seeks information through newspapers, books, and radio, and involves himself
with his community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;reflect&quot;&gt;Reflect&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March: Book One&lt;/em&gt; begins with a portrayal of the great John Lewis’s simple
childhood ability to take stock of his surroundings. On the bus ride to school
in the 1950s, Lewis notices that the roads and buses to school are different for
white children and black children: “The county didn’t bother paving roads into
‘colored’ communities unless it was necessary for white traffic to pass through.
Our bus itself was an old hand-me-down, just like our schoolbooks. I realized
how old it was when we…passed the white children’s buses” (p. 48). He also
notices that the white schools have “…nice playground equipment outside -
nothing like our cluster of small cinderblock buildings with a dirt field out
back for recess” (p. 48). Lewis sees the specific ways in which spaces for black
children receive fewer investments than spaces for white children. On the bus
ride to school, Lewis also remembers: “We drove past prison work gangs almost
every day. The prisoners were always black. As were the folks working in the
fields beyond them. You couldn’t help but notice” (p. 49). During his childhood
in Alabama, Lewis observes the forced labor of black prisoners and the hard
field work of free black people on a daily basis. One year, Lewis’s Uncle Otis
takes him on a special road trip from Alabama to Ohio. Lewis understands that
“Stopping for gas and bathroom breaks took careful planning. Uncle Otis had made
this trip before, and he knew which places along the way offered ‘colored
bathrooms’…it wasn’t until we got into Ohio that I could feel Uncle Otis
relax” (p. 38). Lewis sees that within the United States, travel for people of
color comes with challenges and dangers; he senses his uncle’s wariness during
their journey throughout southern states. As a child, Lewis thinks about what
race means for black children and adults in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learn&quot;&gt;Learn&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As John Lewis becomes aware and interested in his surroundings, he actively
tries to obtain as much information as he can. Lewis reads the newspaper and
listens to the radio in order to learn about current events. In 1954, Lewis
remembers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I read a headline that just turned my world upside down. The U.S. Supreme
Court had handed down its decision in the school desegregation case of Brown
vs. The Board of Education of Topeka. The doctrine of ‘separate but equal’ -
upon which the entire institution of segregation was based - had been ruled
unconstitutional. I was so excited - surely everything was going to change.
p. 53-54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newspaper informs Lewis about national changes. What he reads about the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/event/Brown-v-Board-of-Education-of-Topeka&quot;&gt;Brown vs. Board of
Education&lt;/a&gt;
decision, turns his word “upside down,” and excites him. As he continues to find
more information about the state of the country, he continues to become excited:
“…one Sunday morning in early 1955, I was listening to WRMA…Dr. King’s
message hit me like a bolt of lightning. He applied the principles of the church
to what was happening now, today. It was called the social gospel” (p. 55-56).
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/biography/Martin-Luther-King-Jr&quot;&gt;Martin Luther King
Jr.&lt;/a&gt;’s words help
Lewis make a connection between his religious beliefs and social justice. Lewis
describes Dr. King’s words as electrifying for him. Also in 1955, the police
arrest a woman of color named &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/biography/Rosa-Parks&quot;&gt;Rosa
Parks&lt;/a&gt; when she refuses to sit
in the back of a public bus on account of her race. People begin to talk about
resistance and boycott the buses. Lewis shares, “I listened firsthand to
accounts of what was happening. I followed it almost every day, either in the
papers…or on the radio” (p. 59). Through reading and listening, Lewis learns
about important changes in the law, contemporary leaders such Dr. Martin Luther
King Jr. and Rosa Parks, and the ability people have to change their
environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;act&quot;&gt;Act&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While he is still in high school, Lewis feels motivated to share his convictions
with his community:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dr. King’s example showed me that it was possible to do more as a minister
than what I had witnessed in my own church. I was inspired. So, five days
before my sixteenth birthday, I preached my first public sermon…I was
nervous, but once I warmed up the congregation warmed up too. p. 60&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teenager, Lewis overcomes his own fears to speak before his fellow church
members. He believes in the importance of communication with others. In 1958,
John Lewis attends Jim Lawson’s workshop on non-violence at the First Baptist
Church in Nashville, Tennessee. Lewis and his colleagues decide to resist the
practice of discrimination at the department store lunch counters, where staff
members refuse to serve people of color. Before they go to sit at the lunch
counters however, they must practice their non-violence resistance. Lewis
relates, “…the hardest part to learn - to truly understand, deep in your
heart, was how to find love for your attacker” (p. 82). Because peaceful
protest is a challenge, the young people role-play situations they might
encounter, and teach themselves how to remain calm and loving in their protest.
The activists of the Nashville Student Movement, as they call their effort,
begin sit-ins at the lunch counters, “and at 3:15 pm on May 10, 1960, those six
downtown Nashville stores served food to black customers for the first time in
the city’s history” (p. 120). &lt;em&gt;March: Book One&lt;/em&gt; ends with the department store
lunch counter victory. The integration of the lunch counter shows how Lewis and
other young people come together to plan, practice and effectively enact
resistance to injustice in their community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March: Book One&lt;/em&gt; is a 2013 recollection of John Lewis’s coming of age in mid
20th century America. The graphic novel strives to show young people that if
they pay attention, try to learn as much as they can, and ultimately act on what
they believe is right, they can make positive changes in the world. John Lewis’s
dedication to justice in the 1950s remains a relevant example to young people
over seventy years later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lewis, J., Aydin, A., &amp;amp; Powell, N. (2013). &lt;em&gt;March: Book one&lt;/em&gt;. Top Shelf Productions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="13-15" /><summary type="html">The graphic novel, March: Book One (2013), by Congressman John Lewis, Andrew Aydin, and artist Nate Powell, shares how John Lewis’s productive behaviors as a young man allows him to be an effective force of change even in his school years. Born in Alabama in 1940, John Lewis plays a key role in the American civil rights movement. As a young person, John Lewis observes and thinks carefully about his surroundings, seeks information through newspapers, books, and radio, and involves himself with his community.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/march-book-1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/march-book-1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>